Guide to the Jonathan Edwards Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings of Jonathan Edwards, c. 1720-84; Series I; 10.3; (21 boxes)
  - SERMONS
    - II THESS. 1:7-9: "The wicked at the day of judgment shall receive everlasting vengeance and destruction from the dreadful presence of Christ and from the glory of his power" (p. 3), 1736 May (Box 11, Folder 799)
    - II THESS. 2:13: "He whose work it is to make men holy is the Holy Spirit" (p. 1), 1753 Feb
      See: Box 14, folder 1119
    - II THESS. 3:10-13: "Subject: the sin of idleness, or men's spending their time without diligently following any business" (p. 1), 1752 Jul
      See: Box 14, folder 1120
    - I TIM. 2:5: "Jesus Christ is the great Mediator and Head of union in whom all elect creatures in heaven and earth are united to God and to one another" (p. 9) (Box 11, Folder 800)
    - I TIM. 3:16: "Jesus Christ is both God and man" (p. 1), 1753 Feb
      See: Box 14, folder 1121
    - I TIM. 6:9-10: "An engagedness of mind after worldly profits is a thing attended with all manner of pernicious consequences unto men" (p. 2), 1748 Oct (Box 11, Folder 801)
    - I TIM. 6:15: "God is a being possessed of the most absolutely perfect happiness" (p. 5), 1738 Nov 23 (Box 11, Folder 802)
    - I TIM. 6:19: "The right way of men's improving the opportunities and enjoyments of the present life, is to lay up stores for their support and supply in the time which is to come" (pp. 8-9), 1747 Sep (Box 11, Folder 803)
    - II TIM. 2:26: "Wicked men are the devil's captives" (p. 3), 1733 Oct (Box 11, Folder 804)
    - II TIM. 3:5: "True grace in the heart [?] is a powerful thing" (p. 3), 1737 Jun (Box 11, Folder 805)
    - II TIM. 4:3: "Men are exceeding prone to bring their principles to agree with their lusts" (p. 6), 1738 Apr (Box 11, Folder 806)
    - II TIM. 4:6-8: "Tis comfortable to have a well spent life to think of when one comes to be in the sensible approaches of death" (p. 2), 1746 Oct (Box 11, Folder 807)
    - II TIM. 4:8: "Tis the character of all true saints to love the appearing of Jesus Christ at the last day" (p. 2), 1752 (Box 11, Folder 808)
      "May 1752 sermon at Northampton"
    - TITUS 1:2: "God hath made provision that some Christians should have good reason that true Christians should hope for eternal life" (p. 1), 1751 Dec
      See: Box 14, folder 1122
    - TITUS 2:14: "One main thing that Christ aimed at in what he did and suffered in the work of our redemption was to save men from sin" (p. 3), 1740 Mar (Box 11, Folder 809)
    - TITUS 2:14: "Zeal is an essential virtue of a Christian" (p. 2), 1740 Apr (Box 11, Folder 810)
    - TITUS 3:2: "1. Endeavor to explain the nature of the sin of evil speaking. 2. Speak of the object of it and shew how we are to understand the words when we are directed to speak evil of no man" (p. 1), 1747 May 22 (Box 11, Folder 811)
    - TITUS 3:5: "That there are none saved by their own righteousness" (p. 3), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 812)
    - HEB. 1:3: "Jesus Christ is the shining forth of the Father's glory" (p. 4), 1734 Apr (Box 11, Folder 813)
    - HEB. 1:5: "Christ is a person of transcendent worthiness in the sight of God" (p. 4), 1736, 1752 (Box 11, Folder 814)
    - HEB. 2:1: "When we have heard the word of God we ought to give earnest heed that we don't lose what we have heard" (p. 2), 1733/4 Feb (Box 11, Folder 815)
    - HEB. 2:7-8: "All the works and dispensations of God in all parts of the creation and in all ages of it are such as shew forth the infinite value God has for and delight he has in his Son" (p. 2), 1743 Mar (Box 11, Folder 816)
    - HEB. 2:15: "1. Represent something of the miserable bondage they are that are without any reasonable support against the fears of death. 2. Speak of the deliverance that is to be had by an interest in Christ" (p. 2), 1748 Sept (Box 11, Folder 817)
    - HEB. 2:16: "Subject. Christ's taking on him the seed of Abraham" (p. 2), 1745 Oct (Box 11, Folder 818)
    - HEB. 3:7-11: "They that live under the gospel should take care that it ben't with them as it was with the wicked Israelites of old that God destroyed in the wilderness" (p. 1)
      See: Box 14, folder 1123
    - HEB. 5:7-9: "My design from these words at this time is to contemplate things that Christ shed for sinners, viz. tears and blood" (p. 1), 1741 Aug (Box 11, Folder 819)
    - HEB. 6:7: "Obs. 1. The means of grace to those that live under the gospel are like the showers that often descend on the earth," probably four sermons (p. 2), 1746/7 Jan (Box 11, Folder 820)
    - HEB. 6:8: "Following method: 1. Observe that they that live under grace and don't bring forth good fruits are like ground that the showers of means of rain do only cause to bring forth briers and thorns. 2. That those with whom it is thus are rejected of God. 3. Shew how such are nigh unto cursing. 4. That their end is to be burned" (p. 3) 1746/7 Feb (Box 11, Folder 821)
    - HEB. 6:20:"Jesus Christ is gone to heaven as the forerunner of the saints" (p. 1), 1752 (Box 11, Folder 822)
      "Northampton Lecture May 26, 1752"
    - HEB. 9:12: "Jesus Christ is both the only priest and sacrifice by which eternal redemption is obtained for believers" (p. 5)
      See: Box 14, folder 1124
    - HEB. 9:13-14: "The blood of Christ is sufficient for the perfect taking away the guilt of sin" (p. 6), 1738 Nov (Box 11, Folder 823)
    - HEB. 9:15-16: "The covenant of grace is as it were Christ's last will and testament" (p. 2), 1740, 1753 (Box 11, Folder 824)
    - HEB. 9:27: "All men must certainly die and after death their everlasting state will be determined" (p. 1)
      See: Box 14, folders 1125-1126
    - HEB. 9:27: "All men of all nations all over the world must die" (p. 1), 1750, 1752
      See: Box 14, folder 1127
    - HEB. 9:28: "Christ as his first coming came to bear the sins of his people for the procuring their salvation; at his second coming he will appear without bearing any sin for the bestowment of salvation" (p. 2), 1749/50 Mar (Box 11, Folder 825)
    - HEB. 10:38-39: "Perserverance in holiness is absolutely necessary to salvation" (p. 4), 1736 Sept (Box 11, Folder 826)
    - HEB. 11:7: "When God gives warning of destruction coming upon the world, it concerns men to take care beforehand that they have a refuge where they may hide themselves from that destruction" (p. 2), 1745 Sept (Box 11, Folder 827)
    - HEB. 11:13-14: "This life ought so to be spent by us as to be only a journey towards heaven" (p. 2), 1733, 1753 (Box 11, Folder 828)
      Preached at Boston and at New Haven; preached to Stockbridge Indians
    - HEB. 11:16: "I. This world is an evil country" (p. 1) "II. Heaven is a better country" (p. 4), 1754 Jan
      See: Box 14, folder 1128
    - HEB. 12:2: "We that live under the gospel are called upon to look unto Jesus" (p. 2), 1734 Oct (Box 11, Folder 829)
    - HEB. 12:2-3: "The redeeming love of Christ held out under great difficulties and discouragements" (p. 4) (Box 11, Folder 830)
    - HEB. 12:14: "None will ever be admitted to see Christ but only holy persons" (p. 4), 1733 May (Box 11, Folder 831)
    - HEB. 12:22-24: "I. I would shew how Christians may be said to be come to Mt. Sion" (p. 3), 1740 (Box 11, Folder 832)
    - HEB 12:22-24: "I come now in the second place to shew how Christians are come to the city of the living God, the heavenly Jerusalem" (p. 1), 1740 Apr (Box 11, Folder 833)
    - HEB 12:22-24: "I come now to show in the fourth place how Christians are said to come to the General Assembly and church of the firstborn which are written in Heaven" (p. 1), 1740 Apr (Box 11, Folder 834)
    - HEB 12:22-24: "We are come now to the V. particular in the text, to show how Christians are come to God the Judge of all", 1740 (Box 11, Folder 835)
    - HEB 12:22-24: "This is the VI. particular...How Christians are come to the spirits of just men made perfect" (p. 1), 1740 (Box 11, Folder 836)
    - HEB 12:22-24: "VII. Particular...How Jesus Christ is the Mediator of the New Covenant" (p. 1), 1740 (Box 11, Folder 837)
    - HEB 12:22-24: "I now come to the VIII. and last particular...how Christians are come to the blood of sprinkling that speaketh better things than the blood of Abel" (p. 1), [1740] (Box 11, Folder 838)
    - HEB. 12:29: "God is a consuming fire" (p. 3), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 839)
    - HEB. 12:29: "God himself is the fire that shall destroy and consume wicked men" (p. 1), 1742 May (Box 11, Folder 840)
    - HEB. 13:7-8: ["Farewell sermon to the Indians in Stockbridge, Jan. 8"], incomplete, [17]58 Jan
      See: Box 14, folder 1129
    - HEB. 13:8: "Jesus Christ is the same now that he ever has been and ever will be" (p. 3), 1738 Apr (Box 11, Folder 841)
    - HEB.13:17: "1. That the ministers of the gospel have the souls of men committed to their care by the Lord Jesus Christ..." (p. 4), 1743 Jun 8 (Box 11, Folder 842)
      "Ordination of Mr. Judd"
    - JAMES 1:12 "The doctrine was, that those who love Christ shall receive of him a crown of life" (p. 1), n.d.
      See: Box 14, folder 1130
    - JAMES 1:12: "God's manner is first to try the grace of true saints and then to crown it" (p. 2), 1744 May (Box 11, Folder 843)
    - JAMES 1:13: "Tis impossible that God should be under any temptation to do anything that is evil" (p. 2), 1733 Apr (Box 11, Folder 844)
    - JAMES 1:17: "That God is the Father of lights" (p. 4), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 845)
    - JAMES 1:25: "In God's service is perfect and glorious liberty" (p. 3)
      See: Box 14, folder 1131
    - JAMES 1:26: "Bridling the tongue is a great & essential part of religion," two sermons (p. 3), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 846)
    - JAMES 2:18: "A manifestation of godliness in a man's life and walk is a ground of others' charity concerning his godliness than any account that he better gives about it in words," three sermons (p. 6), 1736 May (Box 11, Folder 847)
    - JAMES 2:19: "The devils tremble at the thoughts of the wrath of God" (p. 5), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 848)
    - JAMES 2:19: "No such experiences as the devils in hell are the subjects of are any sure sign of grace" (p. 2), 1746 (Box 11, Folder 849)
    - JAMES 3:16: "That envying and contention are things of exceeding pernicious consequences" (p. 4) (Box 11, Folder 850)
    - JAMES 4:14: "The present life is as it were nothing" (p. 1), 1748 Dec (Box 11, Folder 851)
    - I PET. 1:8: "That they live the happiest life in this world, that live a life of love to Jesus Christ beholding him with an eye of faith" (p. 3), 1757, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 852)
      Preached to Stockbridge Indians, July 1757
    - I PET. 1:8: "Three things: loving Christ, believing in Him, rejoicing in Him" (p. 1), 1753 Oct
      See: Box 14, folder 1132
    - I PET. 1:13: "When persons are seeking God's grace and blessing in the appointment, they ought to hope to the end for the bestowment of it" (p. 4) (Box 11, Folder 853)
      "Preached at Lyman's farm"
    - I PET. 1:15: "That Christians are under special obligations to be universally holy in their lives" (p. 4)
      See: Box 14, folders 1133-1134
    - I PET. 1:19: "The blood that Christ shed for sinners was most precious" (p. 3), 1737/8-56 (Box 11, Folder 854)
    - I PET. 2:2-3: "That if persons have ever tasted the sweetness of the word and grace of Christ, they will be longing for more and more of it" (p. 4), 1755 Aug, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 855)
    - I PET. 2:5: "The good works of the godly can't be accepted any other way than as in and through Christ" (p. 5) (Box 11, Folder 856)
    - I PET. 2:8: "It would have been better for some persons if Christ never had come into the world to save sinners" (p. 3), 1733 Aug (Box 11, Folder 857)
    - I PET. 2:9: "I. That true Christians are a chosen generation," five sermons (p. 3), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 858)
    - I PET. 3:4: "That a Christian spirit is of great price in the sight of God" (p. 3), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 859)
    - I PET. 3:10-11: "The instructions and precepts God gives us respecting the business of religion are only instructions to us how to be happy" (p. 1), 1739/40 (Box 11, Folder 860)
      This is a later preaching unit, beginning at the third use of exhortation; beginning unit or units lost
    - I PET. 4:7: "It becomes [us] to be sober and serious and make religion our great business for that reason, that all the things of this world will soon come to an end" (p. 1), 1752 Jan 1
      See: Box 14, folder 1135
    - II PET. 1:10-11: "A life of earnest diligence to abound in grace and in works of piety is the way for us to have an entrance administered to us abundantly into eternal glory" (p. 5), 1738 Feb (Box 12, Folder 861)
    - II PET. 1:16: "That seeing the glory of Christ is what tends to assure the heart of the truth of the gospel" (p. 3) (Box 12, Folder 862)
    - II PET. 1:19: "Divine revelation is like a light that shines in a dark place", 1737 Aug (Box 12, Folder 863)
    - II PET. 1:19: "Divine revelation is like a light that shines in a dark place", 1737 Nov (Box 12, Folder 864)
    - II PET. 2:4: "The fall of the angels that sinned and afterwards became devils" (p. 1), 1753 Feb
      See: Box 14, folder 1136
      Preached to the Stockbridge Indians and Mohawks
    - II PET. 2:14: "That mens being so addicted to any wicked practice that they can't leave it off, it is no excuse to 'em but an aggravation." (p. 3), [ca. 1729-32] (Box 12, Folder 865)
    - I JOHN 2:9: "It is a peculiarly awful thing in some cases that it may be said concerning persons that they are to this very day in darkness" (p. 1), 1742 Jun (Box 12, Folder 866)
    - I JOHN 2:25: "1. What is meant by eternal life" (p. 4), 1743 Jul (Box 12, Folder 867)
    - I JOHN 3:2: "That the godly are designed for unknown and inconceivable happiness"
      See: REV 21:18, Box 14, folders 1146-1147
    - I JOHN 3:2: I. The subjects, sons of God 1. by Regeneration 2. by adoption and given by their relation to Christ" (p. 1) (Box 12, Folder 868)
    - I JOHN 3:9: "That grace is in the hearts of the saints in this world as a seed" (p. 4), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 869)
    - I JOHN 3:10: "All mankind through the whole world are of one of these two sorts, either God's people or the devil's people" (p. 1), 1756 Mar
      See: Box 14, folder 1137
    - I JOHN 3:15: "When a man is converted, eternal life is begun in him" (p. 5), 1738/9, 1755 (Box 12, Folder 870)
    - I JOHN 4:12: "True grace in the hearts of the saints is something divine" (p. 5), 1738 Dec (Box 12, Folder 871)
    - I JOHN 4:14: "The concern that the second person in the Trinity has in the affair of our redemption is this, that he is appointed of the Father to be the Savior of mankind" (p. 1), 1746 Apr (Box 12, Folder 872)
    - I JOHN 4:16: "The spirit of the true saints is a spirit of divine love" (p. 1), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 873)
    - I JOHN 4:19: "That God is first in love to his saints" (p. 1), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 874)
    - I JOHN 5:1-4: "1. Saving faith differs from all common faith in its nature, kind and essence. 2. All that are in a state of salvation obey God's commands not only from fear of hell but love to God, and do love him more than the world" (p. 7), 1750 Jul (Box 12, Folder 875)
    - I JOHN 5:1-4: "1. Saving faith differs from all common faith in its natuessence. 2. All that are in a state of salvation obey god's commands not only from fear of hell, but love to God, and do love him more than the world" (p. 1), 1750 Jul (Box 12, Folder 876)
    - I JOHN 5:2: "1. Tis commonly so with the saints, that some graces are more sensible in them than some others" (p. 3), 1736 Jun (Box 12, Folder 877)
    - I JOHN 5:3: "The true love to God makes the duties he requires of us easy and delightful" (p. 2)
      See: Box 14, folder 1138
    - JUDE 6: "The day of judgement will be a great day" (p. 1), 1744-58 (Box 12, Folder 878)
    - JUDE 12: "Some persons under means of grace are in such a state that they are not only dead but they are as it were twice dead and plucked up by the roots" (p. 1), 1741 Dec (Box 12, Folder 879)
    - JUDE 13: "The wicked in another world shall eternally be overwhelmed with the most dismal and perfect gloominess of mind" (p. 2), 1748/9 Jan (Box 12, Folder 880)
    - JUDE 13: "The misery of the wicked in another world will be as it were everlasting darkness without any light" (p. 1), 1756 Jul
      See: Box 14, folder 1139
    - JUDE 19: "There was a sort of persons in the apostles' day who separated themselves from the steady ministers and churches that pretended to have the Spirit and to be very spiritual, but who really were carnal and had not the spirit of God" (p. 1), 1750 Dec (Box 12, Folder 881)
      "Prepared for a lecture at Westfield," "to Canaan"
    - REV. 1:5: "What I intend at this time to shew what we are taught concerning Christ by these names by which he is his time is called" (p. 1), 1745 Jun (Box 12, Folder 882)
    - REV. 1:5: "1. How he is called a witness 2. That he is the Faithful Witness" (p. 1), 1745 Jun (Box 12, Folder 883)
    - REV. 1:5: "1. How Christ has been among the dead. 2. How he came forth from among the dead. 3. How his being risen from the dead is called a being begotten from the dead. 4. How he is called the first begotten" (p. 1), 1745 Jul (Box 12, Folder 884)
    - REV. 1:5: "He is one that has a kingdom set up in the earth amongst the kings of it" (p. 1), 1745 Jul (Box 12, Folder 885)
    - REV. 1:5-6: "Unto him that loved us... and his father." "In speaking from these words I would 1. Speak of Christ's love to his chosen people here mentioned. 2. [Speak] of those fruits of his love that are here spoken of" (p. 1), "1. "That the blood of Christ is a real atonement for sin" (p. 9), two sermons, 1745 Jul (Box 12, Folder 886)
    - REV. 1:7: "...this coming of Christ at the day of judgement is what I shall make the subject of my present discourse" (p. 1), 1750/1, 1752
      See: Box 14, folder 1140
    - REV. 1:17-18: "Tis a solid foundation of comfort to the people of God, that Christ is one that was dead and is alive and is to die no more" (p. 4), 1734-58 (Box 12, Folder 887)
      "at Springfield"
    - REV. 2:4-5: "When any visible people of God continue long and cold and dead and declining in the things of religion, there is a danger that God will take away their religious advantages" (p. 3) (Box 12, Folder 888)
    - REV. 2:17: "...the subject that I would now handle, viz. that white stone and new name written in it that no man knows but he that receives it" (p. 1), 1742 Dec (Box 12, Folder 889)
    - REV. 2:19: "Tis a very pleasing sight to Jesus Christ, to see his people making progress in grace and good works and the last to be more than the first" (p. 3) (Box 12, Folder 890)
    - REV. 3:5: "That he that overcomes in the spiritual warfare, Christ will confess his name before his Father and before his angels" (p. 4) (Box 12, Folder 891)
    - REV. 3:5: "Christ will not be ashamed hereafter to own each one of them that have been his sincere and faithful followers before his Father and before his angels" (p. 3), 1757, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 892)
    - REV. 3:7: "I would shew how Christ is said to have the key of David. 2. How when he opens no man shutteth. 3. How when he shuts no man opens..." (pp. 1-2), 1741-53 (Box 12, Folder 893)
      "Lecture"; "at Boston"; "Sheffield[?]"; "Eliz[abeth] Town"
    - REV. 3:12: "1. I would shew that those that are, thorough Christians are properly decyphered by that, that they are they that overcome. 2. I would speak particularly of these three promises to such...viz. that Christ will write upon them..." (p. 4), 1740, 1752 (Box 12, Folder 894)
    - REV. 3:15: "That a man had better be a heathen than to differ from 'em only in common light and profession" (p. 2) (Box 12, Folder 895)
    - REV. 3:20: Nothing else is required of us in order to our having an interest in Christ, but that we should find it in our hearts to be willing that Christ should be ours and we his" (p. 5), 1734 Mar (Box 12, Folder 896)
    - REV. 3:20: "I would consider and improve the text... in distinct propositions. I. Christ comes to [the] sinner's door..." (p. 1), 1741 Sept (Box 12, Folder 897)
    - REV. 3:20: "The Lord Jesus Christ by coming into the world and dying for sinners has obtained salvation for all such as will repent and turn from their sins and give their hearts to him" (p. 1), 1750/1 Feb
      See: Box 14, folder 1141
    - REV. 5:5-6: "There is an admirable conjunction of diverse excellencies in Jesus Christ," three sermons (p. 4), 1736 Aug (Box 12, Folder 898)
    - REV. 5:12: "Christ was worthy of his exaltation upon the account of his being slain" (p. 4), 1756, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 899)
    - REV. 6:13-17: "I. Though now many don't fear God's wrath, the time will come when they will be afraid" (p. 1), 1754 Jul
      See: Box 14, folder 1142
    - REV. 6:15-16: "That wicked men will hereafter earnestly wish to be turned to nothing and forever cease to be that they may escape the wrath of God" (p. 4), 1755, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 900)
    - REV. 6:16: "When gospel grace comes to [be] turned into wrath, that wrath is peculiarly dreadful" (p. 3), 1745, 1753 (Box 12, Folder 901)
    - REV. 6:16: "The weight of rocks and mountains is light in comparison of that wrath of God that shall hereafter come on ungodly men" (p. 1), 1746/7, 1757 (Box 12, Folder 902)
    - REV. 7:1-3: "In the time of Great public commotions and calamities God will take thorough and effectual care that his servants shall be safe" (p. 6), 1740/1 Feb 26 (Box 12, Folder 903)
      "Fast for success in the war"
    - REV. 7:17: "The shepherd that leads and feeds the church of saints like a flock is himself a lamb" (p. 4), 1740, 1757 (Box 12, Folder 904)
    - REV. 8:2-3: "The prayers of saints is a great and principal means of carrying on the great designs of Christ's kingdom in the world" (p. 1), 1742 Jul (Box 12, Folder 905)
    - REV. 12:1: "I would 1. shew how the church of true saints by her union with Christ is clothed in the sun; 2. I would shew that this is a great wonder; and then would make some application" (p. 2), 1741 Jul (Box 12, Folder 906)
      "at Canaan, at Boston, Portsmouth, Stockbridge"
    - REV. 14:3: "First, I would shew how that those that [are] Christ's redeemed ones in the holy praises they offer up to God, do sing a new song. Secondly, how that no man can learn that song but they..." (p. 5), 1740, 1752 (Box 12, Folder 907)
      Thanksgiving sermon in 1740
    - REV. 14:3: "1...the nature of the redemption of God's elect. 2...what is meant when they are said to be redeemed from the earth" (p. 1), 1741 Nov (Box 12, Folder 908)
    - REV. 14:4: "The saints are those that God has chosen out of all the world to be for him as his part and portion" (p. 1), 1756 Feb
      See: Box 14, folder 1143
    - REV. 14:13: "I. ...how that those that die in the Lord are blessed, and II. ...those reasons given of their blessedness, viz. that they shall rest" (p. 3) (Box 12, Folder 909)
    - REV. 14:13: "When the saints depart out of this into another world, their works do follow them" (p. 4), 1736, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 910)
      "On occasion of the death of Mrs. Stoddard who died Feb. 10, 1736"
    - REV. 14:13: "The proper and appointed season of Christians' rest from the difficulties and labors of their course is after death" (p. 1), 1742/3 Feb (Box 12, Folder 911)
    - REV. 14:14: "Our Lord Jesus Christ is crowned with glory" (p. 3), incomplete, 1736 Oct (Box 12, Folder 912)
    - REV. 14:14: "Obs. 1. the righteous and wicked are both the Lords..." (p. 3) "Obs 2. There are certain appointed and remarkable seasons for the ingathering of both elect and reprobate" (p. 5), 1741 Sept (Box 12, Folder 913)
    - REV. 14:15: "Subject... is, the saints growing ripe for heaven" (p. 4), 1753/4 Jan (Box 12, Folder 914)